<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on João Galego</title><link>https://jgalego.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on João Galego</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 10:48:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jgalego.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon Lookout for Vision</title><link>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/amazon-lookout-for-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 16:15:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/amazon-lookout-for-vision/</guid><description>Defect Detection with Amazon Lookout for Vision AWS has announced the release of a handful of products and services geared towards helping industrial customers and partners in their journey to digital transformation. Under the umbrella term of AWS for Industrial, these offerings, which include not only services but also devices e.g. Amazon Monitron and full-blown solutions e.g. Amazon SageMaker for Predictive Maintenance, cover a lot of interesting use-cases and industry-relevant workloads in such areas as Production &amp;amp; Asset Optimization and Quality Management.</description></item><item><title>Stuff</title><link>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 16:27:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/</guid><description>WBME ML Workshop</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://jgalego.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 10:48:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgalego.github.io/about/</guid><description>Who am I? I am a certified Physics nerd and an amateur forensic scientist with a keen interest in solving interesting and demanding problems. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as a data analyst, software tester, test automation engineer, DevOps engineer and ML consultant for several companies, in areas ranging from market research to fiber optic telecommunications and mobility. Currently, I work as a DevOps engineer and ML consultant at the Siemens Lisbon Tech Hub, while pursuing a PhD degree in Cognitive Science at Universidade de Lisboa.</description></item><item><title>WBME ML Workshop</title><link>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/wbme-ml-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jgalego.github.io/blog/wbme-ml-workshop/</guid><description>Machine Learning for Medicine and Healthcare For more information about the event, please visit 12th WBME - Workshop on Biomedical Engineering
The ubiquity of algorithms and data is one of the hallmarks of the Information Age. In a world powered by technology, where smartphones have more computing power than all of NASA’s computers during the Apollo missions, algorithms run virtually everything.
However, in the advent of the 4th Industrial Revolution, data is growing faster than it can be analyzed and classic algorithms have been unable to cope with this Big Data explosion.</description></item></channel></rss>